<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culture on Slowlane</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Culture on Slowlane</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rushkoff, a change agent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ruskoff-a-change-agent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ruskoff-a-change-agent/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading two books by Douglas Rushkoff. &amp;ldquo;Program or Be Programmed&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Life Inc&amp;rdquo;. These books have well reasoned arguments that encourage a subversive approach to two pervasive elements of modern life&#xA;The rise of technocratic class that you should join before they take control of to many aspects of your life A fundamental challenge to our modern economic model and the way that plays out in our jobs and life choices This is fascinating stuff and fits into a rare category of books that change the way you view the world around you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BEN - bicycle empowerment network</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/bicycle-empowerment-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/bicycle-empowerment-network/</guid>
      <description>Its Blog Action Day - my plug is for BEN the Bicycle Empowerment Network of Namibia.&#xA;Established by Australian Michael Linke who had previously edited Australian Cyclist, which at the time was Australia&amp;rsquo;s largest circulation cycling magazine, and ReNew, a magazine aimed at people designing, making and using solar, wind and biofuel energy devices, lowering their energy consumption and designing environmentally sustainable houses and businesses.&#xA;Since starting in May 2005, they have distributed more than 7,000 bicycles, 80 bicycle ambulances and 9 community-based bicycle workshops.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity amongst the weapons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/simpicity-amongst-the-weapons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/simpicity-amongst-the-weapons/</guid>
      <description>This week we went to the opening night of a new movie - Son Of A Lion. This is a moving and engaging story set in the tribal region of northern Pakistan, home of the Pashtuns. The typical depiction of Pashtuns in contemporary media brands them as extremist terrorists and followers of Osama Bin Laden. This is not the case for much of the population including those in this simple story.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notebooks and Manifestos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/notebooks-and-manifestos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/notebooks-and-manifestos/</guid>
      <description>I have love notebooks, especially interesting quirky ones that help me feel creative.&#xA;My latest notebook is the Makers Notebook from Make magazine. Its modelled after a lab book with graph paper pages. Solidly bound and with loads and useful (and just plain weird) data in the back pages. Included in the book are two manifestos, The Makers Bill of Rights and a Crafters Manifesto. Here is an extract&#xA;People get satisfaction for being able to create/craft things because they can see themselves in the objects they make.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A slow sunday at the art gallery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-sunday-art-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-sunday-art-gallery/</guid>
      <description>We wandered along to the Art Gallery of NSW today for our Slow Sunday. I wanted to take another look at the Harold Cazneaux exhibition. It is the most inspiring collection of photographic images. Wonderful use of light and location, especially when you consider the equipment that he was using compared to what we have available today. The images are highly atmospheric and clearly present themselves as art.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Cazneaux was the leading exponent in Australia of the school of &amp;lsquo;pictorial photography.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resurgence slow sundays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-sundays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-sundays/</guid>
      <description>The latest issue of Resurgence has arrived and it looks a beauty. At quick skim reveals the usual combination of thoughtful articles and fabulous images.&#xA;In the spirit of Ghandi&amp;rsquo;s use of spinning as an act of defiance, Resurgence have chosen baking bread as the theme of their first Slow Sunday.&#xA;In each issue of the magazine we will nominate one Sunday when we invite our members to take part in simple actions that symbolise a rejection of commercialism, a passion for the planet and a desire for change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clear thinking - well informed outspoken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/clear-thinking-and-outspoken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/clear-thinking-and-outspoken/</guid>
      <description>No its not this author, although we can aspire&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m referring to George Monbiot, who&amp;rsquo;s new book Bring on the Apocalypse - Six Arguments for Global Justice has leapt to the top of my reading pile. To do that it displaced Nicholas Shakespeares book Secrets of the Sea which I reserved at the library with great anticipation due to my attachment to stories about Tasmania. Not to mention any number of magazines and other tempting material.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
