<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Slowlane</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Slowlane</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lost in this beautiful world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/lost-in-this-beautiful-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/lost-in-this-beautiful-world/</guid>
      <description>I have been enjoying the album Lost in this beautiful world by Jon Lacey. It&amp;rsquo;s a melodic piano and guitar driven folk album with an authentic feel, partly due to the raw quality of Jon&amp;rsquo;s voice. The songs are introspective and engaging.&#xA;I discovered Jon&amp;rsquo;s music while searching for recordings by one his collaborators on this album Tom McConville. We saw Tom play at the Marine Theatre in Lyme Regis during our last visit to England in October 2011.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Listening</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/new-listening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/new-listening/</guid>
      <description>!&#xA;Album by Chris Smither&#xA;I first heard Chris at the Blue Mountains Music Festival a few years ago, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see he is coming back again this year. We loved his music and went back to see his show again the next day. This new album is excellent.&#xA;I have nearly all of Van&amp;rsquo;s albums and this continues his return to form after a bit of a slump a few albums ago.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shakuhachi festival world masters concert</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/shakuhachi-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/shakuhachi-festival/</guid>
      <description>Just returned from a concert that was the major public event of the 5th World Shakuhachi Festival. This gathering was a rare opportunity to see and hear some of the worlds foremost players and was an extraordinary experience. Tonights concert featured pieces played on Shakuhachi, Koto, Shamisen and harp. A musical and accomplished Australian Aboriginal welcome ceremony was performed by Matthew Doyle. A mass playing of Temuke by the festival participants was a highlight.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
