<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mind on Slowlane</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/mind/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mind on Slowlane</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/mind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Models for decision making</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/decision-making-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/decision-making-models/</guid>
      <description>I like this introduction to decision making techniques at Creative Market.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Some decisions appear to be relatively straight forward until you take a step back and look at the entire picture with a fresh perspective. You may notice that there are a variety of factors that actually impact a choice or decision that you did not notice before.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The post also features a nice mind map example from Learning Fundamentals focused on personal actions for reducing climate change impacts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Obstacles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/overcoming-obstacles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/overcoming-obstacles/</guid>
      <description>This inspirational talk by Nick White at the Wellington Ignite Conference gives an insight into what its like for an avid public speaker to overcome head and neck cancer and the loss of his voice. via Presentation Zen</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living with introverts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/living-with-introverts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/living-with-introverts/</guid>
      <description>Insightful guide to living with an introvert, rings true and definitely worth a look.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depression and getting help</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/depression-getting-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/depression-getting-help/</guid>
      <description>This article was linked by Macdrifter overnight and, as is often the case, Gabe has come up with gem. It&amp;rsquo;s by Rob Delaney a US comedian, reflecting on his depression and the importance of getting help. Read it here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dividing camels</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dividing-camels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dividing-camels/</guid>
      <description>The traditional teaching stories of the Sufi&amp;rsquo;s are often intriguing. One of my favourites is known as Dividing Camels. I originally came across it in Idries Shah&amp;rsquo;s book Thinkers of the East.&#xA;There was once a Sufi who wanted to make sure that his disciples would, after his death, find the right teacher of the Way for them.&#xA;He therefore, after the obligatory bequests laid down by law, left his disciples seventeen camels, with this order:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elegant deep or beautiful explanations-at-edge-2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/deep-or-beautiful-explanations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/deep-or-beautiful-explanations/</guid>
      <description>Some fascinating ideas explored at the Annual Edge contributions for the most deep, elegant or beautiful explanation.&#xA;Responses | 2012 Annual Question | Edge&#xA;(Via www.edge.org)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing one thing at a time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/one-thing-at-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/one-thing-at-a-time/</guid>
      <description>The Magic of Doing One Thing at a Time:&#xA;Excellent reminder from HBR to focus on doing one thing well&#xA;Tell the truth: Do you answer email during conference calls (and sometimes even during calls with one other person)? Do you bring your laptop to meetings and then pretend you&amp;rsquo;re taking notes while you surf the net? Do you eat lunch at your desk? Do you make calls while you&amp;rsquo;re driving, and even send the occasional text, even though you know you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding significance in a world of distraction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-world-of-distraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-world-of-distraction/</guid>
      <description>Really good material here from Becoming Minimalist.&#xA;Finding Significance in a World of Distraction&#xA;For example, the distraction of a lucrative and powerful career has the opportunity to distract us from using our talents to benefit our immediate community. The distraction of maintaining a large and perfect home may pull us from caring for the people living in it. The urge to check up on our Facebook friends steals more of our time than the friends right in front of us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversify your dreams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dream-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dream-diversity/</guid>
      <description>Great post from HBR that calls out the danger of simplifying your dreams down to a narrow outcome that can setup a black and white success or failure scenario. One tool they describe to help avoid this is the &amp;ldquo;folder of gratitude&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Diversify Your Dreams&#xA;So how do you start moving from one dream to many? A practical tip I&amp;rsquo;ve seen work well is to develop a &amp;ldquo;folder of gratitude,&amp;rdquo; a constantly-updated list of all the things in life you&amp;rsquo;re grateful for.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking for meaning by paying attention</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/paying-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/paying-attention/</guid>
      <description>This stimulating post from Art Markman at HBR.org has a focus on Innovation.&#xA;It turns out that if you practice finding the meanings of proverbs, you can get better at finding the same kind of essential definitions of problems you are trying to solve. Describing problems in this way will help you retrieve the knowledge you have that is most likely to lead to innovative problem solutions.&#xA;Ultimately, the key to innovation is not to &amp;ldquo;think different,&amp;rdquo; but rather, to think about different things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to accomplish more by doing less</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/accomplish-more-by-doing-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/accomplish-more-by-doing-less/</guid>
      <description>Rings true to my own experience How to Accomplish More by Doing Less&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s not just the number of hours we sit at a desk in that determines the value we generate. It&amp;rsquo;s the energy we bring to the hours we work. Human beings are designed to pulse rhythmically between spending and renewing energy. That&amp;rsquo;s how we operate at our best. Maintaining a steady reservoir of energy — physically, mentally, emotionally and even spiritually — requires refuelling it intermittently</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining physical social and mental fitness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/social-and-mental-fitness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/social-and-mental-fitness/</guid>
      <description>Since I subscribed to the Harvard Business Review blog posts I have seen a steady stream of sharply observed and well thought out pieces. Many are aimed at corporate efficiency however a good smattering challenge the existing order and some are just timely good advice like this one&#xA;Maintaining Physical, Social and Mental Fitness for Peak Performance&#xA;**Mental fitness **involves the following seven practices — some of which cross over into the physical and social domains: good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep (7-8 hours is recommended), physical activity, focus, reflection, down time, connecting time, and play time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trading as video game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/trading-and-video-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/trading-and-video-games/</guid>
      <description>An interesting article from the Atlantic which compares the modern derivates trading environment with playing a sophisticated computer game.&#xA;Trading as a high-stakes video game&#xA;Worth reading through as it speculates that the scenario described will become a component of more jobs in the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things that matter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/things-that-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/things-that-matter/</guid>
      <description>Seth Godin has published a free ebook, &amp;ldquo;Things that matter&amp;rdquo;. It contains over 70 short essays from todays leading thinkers. Definitely worth a read. I found resonances in many of the entries however the following extract from Howard Mann caught my attention as its a phenonmena I see growing daily.&#xA;We walk the streets with our heads down staring into 3-inch screens while the world whisks by doing the same. And yet we’re convinced we are more connected to each other than ever before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting things off</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/putting-things-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/putting-things-off/</guid>
      <description>Putting Things Off has a nice post about changing the way we work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pursuing a simpler life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-simpler-lfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-simpler-lfe/</guid>
      <description>Zen Habits a frequent and popular contributor of articles that cover many aspects of moving towards a simpler life have published a summary of their articles focused on simplicity.&#xA;Check it out </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healing power of chooks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/healing-power-of-chooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/healing-power-of-chooks/</guid>
      <description>This post has been in my mind since I saw a wonderful program ABC TV. The program “Rare Chicken Rescue” has two themes, one is depression and the other is about rescuing rare chicken breeds. Both subjects are interesting however it was the role that keeping chickens played in rescuing Mark Tully from depression that really struck a chord.&#xA;When we lived on the North Coast of NSW we kept about 20 odd chickens and 3 ducks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing information overload</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/information-overload/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/information-overload/</guid>
      <description>Saw this great cartoon over at Devon-Technologies which I have been visiting lately as I start to tackle my own information overload.&#xA;Devon-Technologies make some very sophisticated software for the mac, I am exploring DevonThink Professional, an amazingly powerful database.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
