<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Slowlane</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Slowlane</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daily Rituals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/daily-rituals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/daily-rituals/</guid>
      <description>Great infographic post at infowetrust via the Huffington Post and macademic that shows the daily ritual of interesting historical figures. Smoking, coffee and beer appear frequently.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture and online learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-and-online-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-and-online-learning/</guid>
      <description>After years of exposure to Permaculture and having spent several years a decade ago implementing a disparate set of its common patterns at our previous property in Northern NSW, I am now taking a much deeper dive into it after enrolling in Geoff Lawton&amp;rsquo;s Online Permaculture Design Course. Its been running a few weeks now and my partner and I are both finding it a revelation. So many concepts and themes that we had previously read about but not really understood are suddenly making sense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sleep apnoea, A success story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/sleep-apnoea-success-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/sleep-apnoea-success-story/</guid>
      <description>Interesting article in The Magazine - Heavy Breathing.&#xA;I blogged previously about my own experiences with this disorder - fortunately, my case is less severe than the authors&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Obstacles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/overcoming-obstacles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/overcoming-obstacles/</guid>
      <description>This inspirational talk by Nick White at the Wellington Ignite Conference gives an insight into what its like for an avid public speaker to overcome head and neck cancer and the loss of his voice. via Presentation Zen</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting to the root of the problem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-root-of-our-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-root-of-our-problem/</guid>
      <description>Excellent writing as usual from Monbiot, pointing to the underlying causes of the unfolding Eco crisis http://www.monbiot.com/2012/12/03/forbidden-planet</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The failure of international politics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/international-political-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/international-political-failures/</guid>
      <description>Stirring writing “After Rio, we know. Governments have given up on the planet” by George Monbiot in reaction to the collapse of the Rio Summit. He still finds reasons to continue to make efforts towards preserving the biosphere. Its clear however that we cannot look to governments and international agreements to do anything significant.&#xA;Was it too much to have asked of the world’s governments, which performed such miracles in developing stealth bombers .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ongoing challenge of how to spend your time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/how-to-spend-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/how-to-spend-your-time/</guid>
      <description>There has been a continuous stream of media about finding your passion and reviewing your working life against higher goals. This post from workawesome is a nice summary, and once it referred to the Eightfold Path and Right Livelihood I had to link it.&#xA;Is it a Job, Career or Your True Calling?:&#xA;What is it that you love doing the most? What are you passionate about and what brings you alive?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off the map</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/off-the-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/off-the-map/</guid>
      <description>I noticed this post recommending the movie &amp;ldquo;Off The Map&amp;rdquo; recently.&#xA;We watched it last night and really enjoyed it. We have been talking about it on and off all day today which is the sign of a movie that has gotten under our skin. I particularly liked the understated direction that let the landscape and the story unfold without joining all the dots for the viewer. Fascinating also to see the homesteading life depicted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sopa what can make a difference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/sopa-can-make-a-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/sopa-can-make-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>Macdrifter is a straight shooter, in this post &amp;ldquo;Man Up&amp;rdquo; he calls for direct action against SOPA. I like the style and support the cause&#xA;Man Up.&#xA;Banners and Cartoons are not going to create the change most internet users want. I know it’s not something I care to waste time on. Instead, I’m gathering links and writing this post. (Via Macdrifter)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crisis of faith in the financial system</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/crisis-of-faith-in-the-financial-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/crisis-of-faith-in-the-financial-system/</guid>
      <description>Thought provoking post by Adam Richardson at Harvard Business Review on the levels of abstraction implicit in the financial system and the trust that is required from all participants for it to continue to operate.&#xA;Crisis of Faith in the Financial System&#xA;From Bernie Madoff to derivatives to the housing bubble to dubious AAA credit ratings, we continue to find new ways to encourage people to make financial leaps of faith.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook and ads</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/facebook-adds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/facebook-adds/</guid>
      <description>This is right on the money - so to speak.&#xA;Facebook and Ads&#xA;ReadWriteWeb&#xA;If you pay for a product, you’re a customer. If you don’t, you’re the product. On Facebook, you are the product. The difference between content and advertising continues to slip.&#xA;(Via inessential.com)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspiring blogger - Matt Gemmell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/matt-gemmell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/matt-gemmell/</guid>
      <description>Matt Gemmell is such a good writer, his post Dear TextMate is a beauty and must reflect the thoughts of many former Textmate fans.&#xA;His recent Simplicity post has me looking into Octopress.&#xA;Another great piece by Matt, Accessibility for iPhone and iPad apps is must read for anyone designing a User Interface. I sent this to a friend who suffers the condition Matt was referring to and he was blown away by the insight shown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US police under the spotlight</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/us-police-under-the-spotlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/us-police-under-the-spotlight/</guid>
      <description>A video of a US policeman calmly capsicum spraying unarmed sitting protestors has created an international storm. James Fallows has exhaustive coverage and Mark Bernstein summarises the story with key links and adds his own view in this excellent post Shame&#xA;The walk of shame, as UC Davis Chancellor Katehi walks to her car before rows of silent students, was extraordinary. James Fallows wrote of the affectless sadism of the campus police, captured forever in film.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VW and the darkside</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/vw-the-dark-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/vw-the-dark-side/</guid>
      <description>Sophisticated campaign orchestrated by Greenpeace using the same Star Wars theme that feature in the latest VW adds. The aim is to raise pressure on Volkswagen to put more effort into bringing its green technology to bear across its fleet. Worth checking the video&amp;rsquo;s out and sign up..&#xA;There is good in Volkswagen. We feel it -&#xA;Volkswagen is a big part of many of our lives – indeed many rebel vehicles are VWs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rushkoff speaks to occupy movement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ruskoff-and-occupy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ruskoff-and-occupy/</guid>
      <description>Douglass Rushkoff is always worth reading, here is a rousing speech he gave to Occupy Wallstreet&#xA;Occupy Reality - Transcript&#xA;You are not fighting against people, but against a machine.It was put in place over 500 years ago.&#xA;By a wealthy elite - trying to repress a booming peer to peer economy.&#xA;Those people are all dead, but their program lives on.&#xA;(Via Douglas Rushkoff)&#xA;As he says in the opening lines this speech covers the material that is exhaustively documented in his book Life Inc which is a fascinating read.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The innovators secret weapon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/innovators-secret-weapon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/innovators-secret-weapon/</guid>
      <description>Great post over at MyMicroISV from Jarie Bolander. Very timely for me as I in the process to creating a day off a week to allow time to grow a new venture.&#xA;The Innovator’s Secret Weapon&#xA;Keep an idea journal: An idea journal is an invaluable tool to find trends and cluster ideas. Just reading through a journal can give you all sorts of inspiration. Have a hobby: Hobbies are great to spark creativity and innovation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Occupying wallstreet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/occupying-wallstreet-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/occupying-wallstreet-2/</guid>
      <description>Tim Bray on Occupying Wall Street:&#xA;• A large number of people in the finance business enriched themselves to the tune of billions in a manner that feels essentially like bald-faced theft. Nobody has been punished. Very few of these people even experienced much in the way of financial setbacks, because they were bailed out with other people’s money. As in, yours &amp;amp; mine.&#xA;• The general degree of inequality, whether measured in money or power, seems unreasonable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CNN occupy wall street</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/occupying-wallstreet-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/occupying-wallstreet-1/</guid>
      <description>I had missed the interesting social experiments Ruskofff describes, the local media is adopting its usual superficial view.&#xA;CNN: Occupy Wall Street is not a Protest but a Prototype&#xA;“Occupy” is anything but a protest movement. That’s why it has been so hard for news agencies to express or even discern the “demands” of the growing legions of Occupy participants around the nation, and even the world. Just like pretty much everyone else on the planet, occupiers may want many things to happen and other things to stop, but the occupation is not about making demands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Save our inboxes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/save-out-inboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/save-out-inboxes/</guid>
      <description>Chris Andersons&amp;rsquo; email charter is well worth checking out and following. I especially like rule 2 - Short and Slow is not Rude.&#xA;emailcharter</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groups with more women are more intelligent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/women-and-group-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/women-and-group-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>Tom Malone on collective intelligence and the “genetic” structure of groups&#xA;The average intelligence of the people in the group and the maximum intelligence of the people in the group doesn’t predict group intelligence.&#xA;and&#xA;So how do you engineer groups that can problem-solve effectively? First of all, seed them with, basically, caring people. Group intelligence is correlated … with the average social sensitivity — the openness, and receptiveness, to others — of a group’s constituents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The franklin river campaign - 25 years on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-franklin-river-campaign-25-years-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-franklin-river-campaign-25-years-on/</guid>
      <description>25 years since the Franklin River Campaign&#xA;In July 1983 the Australian High Court ruled the Franklin Dam could be stopped by the new Federal Labour Government against the wishes of the Tasmanian State government.&#xA;Prior to this over 1000 people from all over Australia and the world had travelled down to the river site camps and been arrested in a mass act of civil disobedience.&#xA;I was there with a number of friends and it was one of the defining experiences of my life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The franklin river campaign - 25 years on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-franklin-river-campaign-25-years-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-franklin-river-campaign-25-years-on/</guid>
      <description>25 years since the Franklin River Campaign&#xA;In July 1983 the Australian High Court ruled the Franklin Dam could be stopped by the new Federal Labour Government against the wishes of the Tasmanian State government.&#xA;Prior to this over 1000 people from all over Australia and the world had travelled down to the river site camps and been arrested in a mass act of civil disobedience.&#xA;I was there with a number of friends and it was one of the defining experiences of my life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frightened by voluntary simplicity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/voluntary-simplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/voluntary-simplicity/</guid>
      <description>An article in the New York Times here tells of a couple who are shedding their possessions prior to starting a new life as organic farmers. What I found interesting was that they have had some hostile reactions on the blog they are keeping to document the journey. I suspect that many people find the idea of others who are stepping outside the norm and “letting it all go by” to be threatening.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New perspectives on money</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/money-perspectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/money-perspectives/</guid>
      <description>The May/June issue of Resurgence has arrived and it looks very interesting.&#xA;Its a special focus issue titled &amp;ldquo;The money delusion: In search of true wealth&amp;rdquo;. It kicks off with an excellent editorial from Satish Kumar which introduces the topic.&#xA;Here are a few quotes to give you a flavour of the article:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Let us be clear. Money is not wealth. It is a delusion to think that money is wealth.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
