<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slowlane</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Slowlane</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 21:50:31 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 21:50:31 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>I continue to be interested in music, alternative lifestyles and technology which have been with me since high school in the 1970&amp;rsquo;s.&#xA;Over the years I have been an environmental activist, natural therapist and ended spending most of my working life in IT.&#xA;You can find my occasionally updated blog here</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 21:50:31 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/now/</guid>
      <description>(This is a now page, and if you have your own site, you should make one, too.)&#xA;Updated Aug 7, 2024 Our Campervan has arrived and we’ve planned a few short trips to shake out any problems and learn how it all works.&#xA;Regularly reminding myself that I don’t need to keep thinking about my next “career”, instead I just need to relax into this new phase.&#xA;Updated May 21, 2024.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Lucky Find</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-lucky-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-lucky-find/</guid>
      <description>Reading John Connell’s “The Running Book” with its evocative portrayal of the Irish landscape prompted me to dig out this catalogue of black &amp;amp; white photographs by Giles Norman. I seem to remember we picked it up at his studio in Kinsale back in the early 1990’s. Beautiful moody landscape and street photography.&#xA;We also had the best Seafood Chowder ever at a pub by the beach at Kinsale1. Since then all Seafood Chowders have been measure against the Kinsale Scale.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tree Poems 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/tree-poem-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/tree-poem-1/</guid>
      <description>KINSHIP by Ursula K. Le Guin&#xA;Very slowly burning, the big forest tree&#xA;stands in the slight hollow of the snow melted around it by the mild, long&#xA;heat of its being and its will to be&#xA;root, trunk, branch, leaf, and know&#xA;earth dark, sun light, wind touch, bird song.&#xA;Rootless and restless and warmblooded, we&#xA;blaze in the flare that blinds us to that slow,&#xA;tall, fraternal fire of life as strong</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sydney Ceramics Galleries</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/sydney-ceramics-galleries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/sydney-ceramics-galleries/</guid>
      <description>There are some excellent galleries in Sydney that focus on displaying the work of local artists and providing exhibition space.&#xA;I am sure its a labour of love for most of the gallery owners as the market is not large and the work required to mount a successful exhibition is signifcant.&#xA;Chinaclay Kerrie Lowe Sabbia If in the mood to travel further afield, the galley at the Sturt College in Mittagong always has an eclectic mix of work in particular furniture and ceramics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inhabit Movie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/inhabit-movie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/inhabit-movie/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2013 a couple of filmmakers bravely took on the risk of making a high quality movie about the Permaculture movement in North America. Once they had shot the footage, they launched a kickstarter project to raise funds to complete the project last year.&#xA;The movie, Inhabit was recently released. Its availble from Vimeo and also through the Yekra project, an innovative distribution channel that enables media creators to sell their product without having to deal with the traditional players.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ceramic Destinations in Tokyo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ceramics-destinations-in-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ceramics-destinations-in-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>The most popular post on Slowlane has been Ceramics Destinations in Kyoto, this post seeks to provide the same information for a Tokyo visitor.&#xA;Mingeikan Also known as the Japan Folk Crafts Museum. Soetsu Yanagi 1 created this museum to display his collection of mingei items (daily necessities made by common people using local materials)It displays a collection of mingei pottery, textiles and lacquer ware. Feature exhibitions are also held regularly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arkansas Living Treasures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/arkansas-living-treasures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/arkansas-living-treasures/</guid>
      <description>Following a link from Fine Woodworking I came across an inspiring collection of videos featuring a group of traditional craftspeople who live in the US state of Arkansas.&#xA;The state has sponsored the production of a movie series featuring each craftsman talking about their work and practising in their studios.&#xA;Something that stands out is the advanced age of some of the artists who are still practising. Chair maker Dallas Bump is 94 and fiddle maker Violet Hensley was still making well into her 90&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making and Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/making-and-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/making-and-work/</guid>
      <description>I describe myself as a Maker, for me the term is a indicator of where my inspiration and satisfaction are found. This has generally been realised in the workshop making objects with wood and more recently clay. Its harder to find in the work I do as a Solution and Enterprise architect. Aspects are definitely present, as myself or my team are generally involved with a larger to team to create and implement a new software capability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Rituals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/daily-rituals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/daily-rituals/</guid>
      <description>Great infographic post at infowetrust via the Huffington Post and macademic that shows the daily ritual of interesting historical figures. Smoking, coffee and beer appear frequently.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Vision of the Future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-vision-of-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-vision-of-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Wolfram at SXSW The link above is to a transcript of Stephen Wolframs SXSW talk, a mind boggling run down of the incredible computational power that his firm of rolling out.&#xA;The potential to harness these capabilities into new types of software is enormous.&#xA;Worth reading right through for a glimpse of the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making a Flamenco Guitar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/making-a-flamenco-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/making-a-flamenco-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I have linked to this video showing the making of a beautiful guitar before, but its so good its worth another run.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture Online Course Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-online-course-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-online-course-update/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I wrote about the positive experience we were having taking part in Geoff Lawton&amp;rsquo;s Online Permaculture course. Having completed all the online lessons and the quiz we are now working on the practical assignment which is due by the end of August.&#xA;The course continues to stimulate us and our enthusiasm for the material remains strong. Even on evenings when we were tired from a busy day the prospect of some &amp;ldquo;Geoff time&amp;rdquo; was appealing and we had little trouble keeping up the momentum and staying more or less in line with the proposed course outline.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We should build mandolins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/we-should-build-mandolins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/we-should-build-mandolins/</guid>
      <description>Here is another beautiful video celebrating craftsmanship.&#xA;It features Tom Ellis who started building mandolins from his rural workshop in late 1970&amp;rsquo;s. Tom has recently relaunched his instrument line in collaboration with Pava one his co-workers.&#xA;The video was produced by the Fretboard Journal a very high quality magazine that features stories and photo&amp;rsquo;s about guitars, players and makers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture and online learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-and-online-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-and-online-learning/</guid>
      <description>After years of exposure to Permaculture and having spent several years a decade ago implementing a disparate set of its common patterns at our previous property in Northern NSW, I am now taking a much deeper dive into it after enrolling in Geoff Lawton&amp;rsquo;s Online Permaculture Design Course. Its been running a few weeks now and my partner and I are both finding it a revelation. So many concepts and themes that we had previously read about but not really understood are suddenly making sense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jean Nicholas Gerard, a potters potter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-potters-potter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-potters-potter/</guid>
      <description>Goldmark have produced another fascinating &amp;ldquo;day in the life&amp;rdquo; video, this time featuring French potter Jean-Nicholas Gerard who makes beautiful slipware pots.&#xA;Although these videos are obviously produced to promote the artists ahead of upcoming exhibitions at Goldmark, they are in themselves a tremendous service to the ceramics community. The gentle pace and broad scope allow the viewer to be transported into the rhythm of these artists lives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why have Enterprise Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/enterprise-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/enterprise-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Mastering Archimate has worked with T36 in the creation of an excellent video that shows why Enterprise Architecture is important.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost in this beautiful world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/lost-in-this-beautiful-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/lost-in-this-beautiful-world/</guid>
      <description>I have been enjoying the album Lost in this beautiful world by Jon Lacey. It&amp;rsquo;s a melodic piano and guitar driven folk album with an authentic feel, partly due to the raw quality of Jon&amp;rsquo;s voice. The songs are introspective and engaging.&#xA;I discovered Jon&amp;rsquo;s music while searching for recordings by one his collaborators on this album Tom McConville. We saw Tom play at the Marine Theatre in Lyme Regis during our last visit to England in October 2011.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The way of the megapode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/megapode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/megapode/</guid>
      <description>I am with but she&amp;rsquo;s a girl, being a fan of Douglas Adam&amp;rsquo;s book Last Chance to See. As I am also in interested in scripting and other geekery, this post hit all the right notes.&#xA;Our local Megapodes are known as Bush (or Brush) Turkey&amp;rsquo;s and can destroy a productive vege path in seconds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Models for decision making</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/decision-making-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/decision-making-models/</guid>
      <description>I like this introduction to decision making techniques at Creative Market.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Some decisions appear to be relatively straight forward until you take a step back and look at the entire picture with a fresh perspective. You may notice that there are a variety of factors that actually impact a choice or decision that you did not notice before.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The post also features a nice mind map example from Learning Fundamentals focused on personal actions for reducing climate change impacts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sleep apnoea, A success story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/sleep-apnoea-success-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/sleep-apnoea-success-story/</guid>
      <description>Interesting article in The Magazine - Heavy Breathing.&#xA;I blogged previously about my own experiences with this disorder - fortunately, my case is less severe than the authors&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Obstacles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/overcoming-obstacles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/overcoming-obstacles/</guid>
      <description>This inspirational talk by Nick White at the Wellington Ignite Conference gives an insight into what its like for an avid public speaker to overcome head and neck cancer and the loss of his voice. via Presentation Zen</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prioritising organic foods and challenges to paleo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/organic-foods-and-paleo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/organic-foods-and-paleo/</guid>
      <description>Mark Sisson runs a business that promotes a version of the Paleo diet and philosophy (Primal). He writes some excellent posts on his blog that I often find myself nodding in agreement with. A recent post that suggests a prioritised list of what to buy from organic sources is an example.&#xA;What Foods to Buy Organic&#xA;I like this list. In addition, its also important to consider&#xA;Animal welfare. Always look for evidence of best practises in animal welfare and support these growers and suppliers Sourcing food outside of the large supermarket monopolies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvay Conference 1911</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/solvay-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/solvay-conference/</guid>
      <description>Mark Bernstein: Going To Conferences&#xA;Bernstein illustrates his argument by describing the photo below, which brought to my attention that so many these famous scientists were contemporaries.&#xA;There’s a picture in the lobby of the Hotel Metropole in Brussels of the attendees at the first Solvay conference in 1911. Madame Curie is sitting next to Henri Poincaré; they’re both examining a paper and it’s more interesting than the group photo. Behind them, a shockingly young Al Einstein is paying more attention to the photographer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Information Visualisation and Web Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/web-science-posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/web-science-posters/</guid>
      <description>Very interesting diagrams to see at the Web Science Industry Forum Poster Session via Mark Bernstein&#xA;Mark Bernstein, the author of the Tinderbox platform is also a scientist who studies hypertext.&#xA;His recent post contains a link to numerous web science posters developed at various universities.&#xA;Lots of graphic design inspiration to be found here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture ethics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-ethics/</guid>
      <description>I have been interested in Permaculture since 1980 when I stumbled upon a copy of Permaculture 2 in our local bookshop (the same shop also introduced me to The One Straw Revolution and Ecotopia around the same time).&#xA;Over the years I have experimented with various permaculture methods and been fortunate enough to meet Bill Mollison on a number of occasions. One of these was at the Tanelorn Music Festival held at Stroud in the Hunter Valley in 1981, not long after I had discovered the book.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Makers at work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/makers-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/makers-at-work/</guid>
      <description>There is an extensive collection of videos of showcasing makers and their work, at Those Who Make.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s one I particularly enjoyed</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A look behind the increasing prevalence of supermarket-organic-products</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/supermarket-organics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/supermarket-organics/</guid>
      <description>Is Organic Supermarket Food a Lie? Revealing look behind the supermarket green wash. The example is from Europe however it is surely just as relevant here in Australia. The call to action&#xA;Here is what we can do starting today&#xA;* Stop supporting industrial food by buying it. Organic is better than conventional, but still not good.&#xA;* Build relationships with small local farmers that believe in quality and practice sustainable agriculture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Craftsmanship, one mans inspiration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/craftsmanship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/craftsmanship/</guid>
      <description>Moving essay from David Sparks meditating about the influence of his father on his own pursuit of craftsmanship. I am sure that many modern craftsman were inspired to take up the tools for similar reasons, I certainly was growing up in a household where Dad always had a project on the go.&#xA;Craftsmanship and My Father — MacSparky</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualisation techniques</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/visualisation-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/visualisation-techniques/</guid>
      <description>This is interesting, an interactive compilation of data visualisation techniques.&#xA;Quite a few here I didn&amp;rsquo;t recognise. Click on the image to load the full diagram then hover over each cell for an example.&#xA;Via MacSparky</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinas rising soybean consumption-reshaping-western-agriculture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/chinas-soybean-consumption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/chinas-soybean-consumption/</guid>
      <description>Disturbing article by Lester Brown on the PRI website&#xA;&amp;ldquo;..Put simply, saving the Amazon rainforest now depends on curbing the growth in demand for soybeans by stabilizing population worldwide as soon as possible. And for the world’s more affluent people, it means eating less meat and thus slowing the growth in demand for soybeans…&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Where was once pristine Amazon rainforest, soybean harvesters march across the landscape instead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ode to invention, Maira Kalman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/maria-kalman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/maria-kalman/</guid>
      <description>Steve Zeoli posted a link to the work of Maira Kalman in the NY Times today, in this case an enlightening graphic celebration of the inventiveness of Benjamin Franklin. This post was part of a series - &amp;ldquo;The Pursuit of Happiness (2009)&amp;rdquo; - a year long exploration of American History and democracy beginning with a story on the inauguration of Barack Obama.&#xA;Here is the NY Times article -&amp;gt; Can Do</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Made by hand in brooklyn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/made-by-hand-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/made-by-hand-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>Made by Hand is a project creating beautiful videos that celebrate the resurgent maker scene in Brooklyn. Also see this page.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;Made by Hand was created out of the belief that the things we collect, consume, use, and share are part of who we are as individuals. For example, the food that we eat says something about each of us, as do the tools we use and the chairs we rest on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Dermer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-visit-to-john-dermer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-visit-to-john-dermer/</guid>
      <description>In November we travelled down to Kirby&amp;rsquo;s Flat for John Dermer&amp;rsquo;s annual major exhibition.&#xA;Planning to be there early we stayed overnight in Beechworth and arrived at Johns pottery at 10 past nine, assuming we would be the first car in the car park. What a surprise to find about a dozen cars already parked up, even more of a shock was waiting for us when we entered the gallery to find half of the exhibits already proudly bearing their red stickers indicating they were sold.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swedish spoon-maker 1923</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/spoon-maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/spoon-maker/</guid>
      <description>Great video link from The Village Carpenter</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living with introverts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/living-with-introverts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/living-with-introverts/</guid>
      <description>Insightful guide to living with an introvert, rings true and definitely worth a look.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depression and getting help</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/depression-getting-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/depression-getting-help/</guid>
      <description>This article was linked by Macdrifter overnight and, as is often the case, Gabe has come up with gem. It&amp;rsquo;s by Rob Delaney a US comedian, reflecting on his depression and the importance of getting help. Read it here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting to the root of the problem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-root-of-our-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-root-of-our-problem/</guid>
      <description>Excellent writing as usual from Monbiot, pointing to the underlying causes of the unfolding Eco crisis http://www.monbiot.com/2012/12/03/forbidden-planet</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dividing camels</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dividing-camels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dividing-camels/</guid>
      <description>The traditional teaching stories of the Sufi&amp;rsquo;s are often intriguing. One of my favourites is known as Dividing Camels. I originally came across it in Idries Shah&amp;rsquo;s book Thinkers of the East.&#xA;There was once a Sufi who wanted to make sure that his disciples would, after his death, find the right teacher of the Way for them.&#xA;He therefore, after the obligatory bequests laid down by law, left his disciples seventeen camels, with this order:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Challenges of creating for the web</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/creating-for-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/creating-for-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Hilarious comic at The Oatmeal, thanks to Better Mess for the link.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Listening</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/new-listening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/new-listening/</guid>
      <description>!&#xA;Album by Chris Smither&#xA;I first heard Chris at the Blue Mountains Music Festival a few years ago, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see he is coming back again this year. We loved his music and went back to see his show again the next day. This new album is excellent.&#xA;I have nearly all of Van&amp;rsquo;s albums and this continues his return to form after a bit of a slump a few albums ago.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Anarchists Tool Chest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/anarchists-toolchest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/anarchists-toolchest/</guid>
      <description>Just finished reading the Anarchists Tool Chest by Christopher Schwartz. Its inspired me to build my own chest and stock with it quality tools made where possible by small firms and individuals who are keeping the tools needed for traditional woodworking alive. Chris has wicked sense of humour which, once I tuned into it, added a nice touch of levity to the material.&#xA;The book is about what Chris describes as the essential set of tools needed to practise traditional hand tool woodworking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Octopress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2012-10-24-leaving-octopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2012-10-24-leaving-octopress/</guid>
      <description>After some months of not posting due in part to the limitations of Octopress, I have changed buses again. The site is now being built with Rapidweaver and uses the Rapidblog plugin to synch with a blogger account. This allow posting from the Blogger web interface and from IOS blogging apps like Blogsy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ceramics Destinations in Kyoto</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ceramics-destinations-in-kyoto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ceramics-destinations-in-kyoto/</guid>
      <description>The following are worth considering if you are in Kyoto and interested in Ceramics.&#xA;Kawai Kanjiros&amp;rsquo; House We have visited this beautiful old merchants house with its huge climbing kiln several times and always found it rewarding. The enormous climbing kiln and beautifully preserved house are worth spending some time exploring.&#xA;Kawai Kanjiro was a key player in Soetsu Yanangi&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Mingei&amp;rdquo; movement1 in partnership Shoji Hamada, Kenichi Tomimoto and Bernard Leach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mike dodd video</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/mike-dodd-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/mike-dodd-video/</guid>
      <description>Mike Dodd makes beautiful ceramics.&#xA;Goldmark have produced an uplifting video of Mike talking about his work and life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The failure of international politics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/international-political-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/international-political-failures/</guid>
      <description>Stirring writing “After Rio, we know. Governments have given up on the planet” by George Monbiot in reaction to the collapse of the Rio Summit. He still finds reasons to continue to make efforts towards preserving the biosphere. Its clear however that we cannot look to governments and international agreements to do anything significant.&#xA;Was it too much to have asked of the world’s governments, which performed such miracles in developing stealth bombers .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A cabinet makers notebook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-cabinetmakers-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-cabinetmakers-notebook/</guid>
      <description>In interviews with contemporary woodworkers James Krenov’s first book ‘A Cabinetmaker Notebook’ is often cited as the book that changed the course of that person’s life and led to them pursuing a career with wood.&#xA;The book is a meditation on Krenov’s approach to his work. It describes a sensitive and considered approach to the design and construction of several pieces with a friendly conversational tone.&#xA;I stand at my workbench.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guitar zero</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/guitar-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/guitar-zero/</guid>
      <description>I am reading a new book by Gary Marcus a scientist who in his professional life studies languages and cognitive science. In this book he explores the research behind the popular belief that its much more difficult for adults to learn a musical instrument compared to the ease with which children can pick it up. Gary had always harboured a desire to learn the guitar and the book follows his own journey to learn the guitar in his 40’s as he seeks to debunk the assumed wisdom that says its really to late for him to become competent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote posting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2012-06-04-remote-posting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2012-06-04-remote-posting/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post from my iPad using Diet Coda to edit the Octopress post.&#xA;I have now converted the blog from Wordpress and built a workflow for posting from the iPad.&#xA;Not happy worth the load speed of the header so that will probably go, otherwise I really like the simple template that octopress provides.&#xA;One of the challenges looks to be efficient syncing of the locally generated site up to my web host, I am using a Transmit synch but it takes about 15 minutes even if only one page has changed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elegant deep or beautiful explanations-at-edge-2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/deep-or-beautiful-explanations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/deep-or-beautiful-explanations/</guid>
      <description>Some fascinating ideas explored at the Annual Edge contributions for the most deep, elegant or beautiful explanation.&#xA;Responses | 2012 Annual Question | Edge&#xA;(Via www.edge.org)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing one thing at a time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/one-thing-at-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/one-thing-at-a-time/</guid>
      <description>The Magic of Doing One Thing at a Time:&#xA;Excellent reminder from HBR to focus on doing one thing well&#xA;Tell the truth: Do you answer email during conference calls (and sometimes even during calls with one other person)? Do you bring your laptop to meetings and then pretend you&amp;rsquo;re taking notes while you surf the net? Do you eat lunch at your desk? Do you make calls while you&amp;rsquo;re driving, and even send the occasional text, even though you know you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding significance in a world of distraction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-world-of-distraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-world-of-distraction/</guid>
      <description>Really good material here from Becoming Minimalist.&#xA;Finding Significance in a World of Distraction&#xA;For example, the distraction of a lucrative and powerful career has the opportunity to distract us from using our talents to benefit our immediate community. The distraction of maintaining a large and perfect home may pull us from caring for the people living in it. The urge to check up on our Facebook friends steals more of our time than the friends right in front of us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to clean your apps permissions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/clean-app-permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/clean-app-permissions/</guid>
      <description>I found quite a few applications that had permission to my gmail and linkedIn accounts that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember why I granted.&#xA;Definitely worth the small effort involved.&#xA;Take 2 Minutes to Clean Your Apps Permissions</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attack of the wolf mountain chickens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/wolf-mountain-chickens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/wolf-mountain-chickens/</guid>
      <description>This chook post has it all - video, pictures, domes and self feeders. Also some great insight into the chicken management practises at Milkwood Permaculture.&#xA;Attack of the Wolf Mountain Chickens&#xA;(Via Milkwood Permaculture.)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversify your dreams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dream-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dream-diversity/</guid>
      <description>Great post from HBR that calls out the danger of simplifying your dreams down to a narrow outcome that can setup a black and white success or failure scenario. One tool they describe to help avoid this is the &amp;ldquo;folder of gratitude&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Diversify Your Dreams&#xA;So how do you start moving from one dream to many? A practical tip I&amp;rsquo;ve seen work well is to develop a &amp;ldquo;folder of gratitude,&amp;rdquo; a constantly-updated list of all the things in life you&amp;rsquo;re grateful for.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sleep apnea and sonomed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/sleep-apnoea-and-sonomed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/sleep-apnoea-and-sonomed/</guid>
      <description>This article from the BBC describes a sleeping pattern involving two sleeps of about 4 hours with a period of wakefulness in between, known as segmented sleep. It seems there is evidence that this was the normal sleep pattern until the night was pushed back by street lighting at the end of the 16th century.&#xA;During this waking period people were quite active. They often got up, went to the toilet or smoked tobacco and some even visited neighbours.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncloud local wireless networking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/uncloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/uncloud/</guid>
      <description>This looks interesting - another useful step towards Internet independence.&#xA;unCloud — It&amp;rsquo;s not that kind.&#xA;(Via creativeapplications)&#xA;Check out Douglas Rushkoff&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Life Inc - The Movie&amp;rdquo; to see why this matters then read Program or Be Programmed</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ongoing challenge of how to spend your time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/how-to-spend-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/how-to-spend-your-time/</guid>
      <description>There has been a continuous stream of media about finding your passion and reviewing your working life against higher goals. This post from workawesome is a nice summary, and once it referred to the Eightfold Path and Right Livelihood I had to link it.&#xA;Is it a Job, Career or Your True Calling?:&#xA;What is it that you love doing the most? What are you passionate about and what brings you alive?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off the map</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/off-the-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/off-the-map/</guid>
      <description>I noticed this post recommending the movie &amp;ldquo;Off The Map&amp;rdquo; recently.&#xA;We watched it last night and really enjoyed it. We have been talking about it on and off all day today which is the sign of a movie that has gotten under our skin. I particularly liked the understated direction that let the landscape and the story unfold without joining all the dots for the viewer. Fascinating also to see the homesteading life depicted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sopa what can make a difference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/sopa-can-make-a-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/sopa-can-make-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>Macdrifter is a straight shooter, in this post &amp;ldquo;Man Up&amp;rdquo; he calls for direct action against SOPA. I like the style and support the cause&#xA;Man Up.&#xA;Banners and Cartoons are not going to create the change most internet users want. I know it’s not something I care to waste time on. Instead, I’m gathering links and writing this post. (Via Macdrifter)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crisis of faith in the financial system</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/crisis-of-faith-in-the-financial-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/crisis-of-faith-in-the-financial-system/</guid>
      <description>Thought provoking post by Adam Richardson at Harvard Business Review on the levels of abstraction implicit in the financial system and the trust that is required from all participants for it to continue to operate.&#xA;Crisis of Faith in the Financial System&#xA;From Bernie Madoff to derivatives to the housing bubble to dubious AAA credit ratings, we continue to find new ways to encourage people to make financial leaps of faith.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Read one book per week</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/one-book-per-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/one-book-per-week/</guid>
      <description>I will have to adopt an approach like Joshua Beck at Becoming Minimalist) if I am to reduce my reading backlog. Not to mention keeping up to date with exciting new books like those in the Tournament of Books.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fairfield Horseshoe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fairfield-horseshoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fairfield-horseshoe/</guid>
      <description>We had a long and rewarding day walking the Fairfield Horseshoe in the hills around Ambleside. It was mid September 2011 and the weather blessed us with clear skies and warm temperatures which added up to fantastic views.&#xA;Flickr gallery</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking for meaning by paying attention</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/paying-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/paying-attention/</guid>
      <description>This stimulating post from Art Markman at HBR.org has a focus on Innovation.&#xA;It turns out that if you practice finding the meanings of proverbs, you can get better at finding the same kind of essential definitions of problems you are trying to solve. Describing problems in this way will help you retrieve the knowledge you have that is most likely to lead to innovative problem solutions.&#xA;Ultimately, the key to innovation is not to &amp;ldquo;think different,&amp;rdquo; but rather, to think about different things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar sinter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/solar-sinter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/solar-sinter/</guid>
      <description>I am amazed by this, its an incredible project that uses sunlight, 3D printing components and sand to produce glass sculptures. Watch the video right through to understand what is happening.&#xA;Markus Kayser - Solar Sinter Project from Markus Kayser on Vimeo. via CreativeApplications.Net Check out the other Best of 2011 Projects on the site as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drowning in books to read</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/drowning-in-books-to-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/drowning-in-books-to-read/</guid>
      <description>I love books, i enjoy being given them at this time of the year and I enjoy buying them at any time. Unfortunately I sometimes fall behind with reading them.&#xA;The to read pile has grown to the point where I decided I needed to create a list to keep track of them - Omnifocus to the rescue. Listing them like this should discourage me from acquiring any more until I have reduced this backlog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exporting entries from day one to-scrivener-verbum-breviatum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/day-one-to-scrivener/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/day-one-to-scrivener/</guid>
      <description>Brilliant - I was just working out how to do this using Tinderbox which is where I plan to archive the entries.&#xA;Exporting Entries from Day One to Scrivener Verbum Breviatum</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook and ads</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/facebook-adds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/facebook-adds/</guid>
      <description>This is right on the money - so to speak.&#xA;Facebook and Ads&#xA;ReadWriteWeb&#xA;If you pay for a product, you’re a customer. If you don’t, you’re the product. On Facebook, you are the product. The difference between content and advertising continues to slip.&#xA;(Via inessential.com)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to accomplish more by doing less</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/accomplish-more-by-doing-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/accomplish-more-by-doing-less/</guid>
      <description>Rings true to my own experience How to Accomplish More by Doing Less&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s not just the number of hours we sit at a desk in that determines the value we generate. It&amp;rsquo;s the energy we bring to the hours we work. Human beings are designed to pulse rhythmically between spending and renewing energy. That&amp;rsquo;s how we operate at our best. Maintaining a steady reservoir of energy — physically, mentally, emotionally and even spiritually — requires refuelling it intermittently</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspiring blogger - Matt Gemmell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/matt-gemmell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/matt-gemmell/</guid>
      <description>Matt Gemmell is such a good writer, his post Dear TextMate is a beauty and must reflect the thoughts of many former Textmate fans.&#xA;His recent Simplicity post has me looking into Octopress.&#xA;Another great piece by Matt, Accessibility for iPhone and iPad apps is must read for anyone designing a User Interface. I sent this to a friend who suffers the condition Matt was referring to and he was blown away by the insight shown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A book apart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-book-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-book-apart/</guid>
      <description>Just bought a bundle from A Book Apart, excellent value - especially as eBooks.&#xA;I already had the CSS3 book by Dan Cederholm and its a good little book. Its the little part that I particularly like, these days I find I do not have the time to work through large technical books and much prefer condensed focused works like the ones published by A Book Apart. Another thing they have right is providing multiple formats so I can read this on my Kindle and the Macbook Air, the prags led the way on this and another favourite publisher.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dark Sky - how it works</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dark-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dark-sky/</guid>
      <description>This post is a fascinating description of the design of Dark Sky.&#xA;I enjoyed the way the development team used a combination of open source tools, publicly available radar data and some clever numerical analysis rendered into a form that allows the iPhone&amp;rsquo;s GPU to be employed. Great read.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US police under the spotlight</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/us-police-under-the-spotlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/us-police-under-the-spotlight/</guid>
      <description>A video of a US policeman calmly capsicum spraying unarmed sitting protestors has created an international storm. James Fallows has exhaustive coverage and Mark Bernstein summarises the story with key links and adds his own view in this excellent post Shame&#xA;The walk of shame, as UC Davis Chancellor Katehi walks to her car before rows of silent students, was extraordinary. James Fallows wrote of the affectless sadism of the campus police, captured forever in film.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the global money markets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/understanding-global-money-movements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/understanding-global-money-movements/</guid>
      <description>There is a visually striking and information rich diagram from the BBC showing how the Euro countries are indebted to each&#xA;Also check out this incredible graphic from xkcd</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VW and the darkside</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/vw-the-dark-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/vw-the-dark-side/</guid>
      <description>Sophisticated campaign orchestrated by Greenpeace using the same Star Wars theme that feature in the latest VW adds. The aim is to raise pressure on Volkswagen to put more effort into bringing its green technology to bear across its fleet. Worth checking the video&amp;rsquo;s out and sign up..&#xA;There is good in Volkswagen. We feel it -&#xA;Volkswagen is a big part of many of our lives – indeed many rebel vehicles are VWs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rushkoff speaks to occupy movement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ruskoff-and-occupy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ruskoff-and-occupy/</guid>
      <description>Douglass Rushkoff is always worth reading, here is a rousing speech he gave to Occupy Wallstreet&#xA;Occupy Reality - Transcript&#xA;You are not fighting against people, but against a machine.It was put in place over 500 years ago.&#xA;By a wealthy elite - trying to repress a booming peer to peer economy.&#xA;Those people are all dead, but their program lives on.&#xA;(Via Douglas Rushkoff)&#xA;As he says in the opening lines this speech covers the material that is exhaustively documented in his book Life Inc which is a fascinating read.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining physical social and mental fitness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/social-and-mental-fitness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/social-and-mental-fitness/</guid>
      <description>Since I subscribed to the Harvard Business Review blog posts I have seen a steady stream of sharply observed and well thought out pieces. Many are aimed at corporate efficiency however a good smattering challenge the existing order and some are just timely good advice like this one&#xA;Maintaining Physical, Social and Mental Fitness for Peak Performance&#xA;**Mental fitness **involves the following seven practices — some of which cross over into the physical and social domains: good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep (7-8 hours is recommended), physical activity, focus, reflection, down time, connecting time, and play time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The innovators secret weapon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/innovators-secret-weapon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/innovators-secret-weapon/</guid>
      <description>Great post over at MyMicroISV from Jarie Bolander. Very timely for me as I in the process to creating a day off a week to allow time to grow a new venture.&#xA;The Innovator’s Secret Weapon&#xA;Keep an idea journal: An idea journal is an invaluable tool to find trends and cluster ideas. Just reading through a journal can give you all sorts of inspiration. Have a hobby: Hobbies are great to spark creativity and innovation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Occupying wallstreet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/occupying-wallstreet-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/occupying-wallstreet-2/</guid>
      <description>Tim Bray on Occupying Wall Street:&#xA;• A large number of people in the finance business enriched themselves to the tune of billions in a manner that feels essentially like bald-faced theft. Nobody has been punished. Very few of these people even experienced much in the way of financial setbacks, because they were bailed out with other people’s money. As in, yours &amp;amp; mine.&#xA;• The general degree of inequality, whether measured in money or power, seems unreasonable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CNN occupy wall street</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/occupying-wallstreet-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/occupying-wallstreet-1/</guid>
      <description>I had missed the interesting social experiments Ruskofff describes, the local media is adopting its usual superficial view.&#xA;CNN: Occupy Wall Street is not a Protest but a Prototype&#xA;“Occupy” is anything but a protest movement. That’s why it has been so hard for news agencies to express or even discern the “demands” of the growing legions of Occupy participants around the nation, and even the world. Just like pretty much everyone else on the planet, occupiers may want many things to happen and other things to stop, but the occupation is not about making demands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Apple of zen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-apple-of-zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-apple-of-zen/</guid>
      <description>Steve Jobs practised Zen! - the dharma talk below from teacher Peg Syverson (Appamada.org) considers Steve&amp;rsquo;s legacy and how to apply his approach to our lives.&#xA;Many people don’t even know that Steve Jobs practiced Zen. His teacher was Kobun Chino, a beloved Zen teacher who also performed Steve’s wedding to Laurene. Kobun Chino died in 2002 trying to save his five year old daughter Maya when she fell off a dock in Switzerland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This precious life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-precious-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-precious-life/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Because we don’t know when we will die, we get to think of life as an inexhaustible well. Yet everything happens only a certain number of times, and a very small number really. How many more times will you remember a certain afternoon of your childhood, an afternoon that is so deeply a part of your being that you can’t even conceive of your life without it? Perhaps four, five times more, perhaps not even that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Save our inboxes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/save-out-inboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/save-out-inboxes/</guid>
      <description>Chris Andersons&amp;rsquo; email charter is well worth checking out and following. I especially like rule 2 - Short and Slow is not Rude.&#xA;emailcharter</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The future of aviation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/aviation-futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/aviation-futures/</guid>
      <description>Some fascinating images in the Atlantic article linked below - the long distance air travel proposal may well turn out to be the low carbon future of air transport&#xA;What Might Have Been: The French View The French National Library has a wonderful exhibit of prints from 1910, imagining the wonderful new world of the year 2000.&#xA;Long-distance air travel of the future&#xA;read the full post here&#xA;(Via James Fallows : The Atlantic)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 death bed regrets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/death-bed-regrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/death-bed-regrets/</guid>
      <description>Profound - timely.&#xA;Long Term Life Tips Top 5 Regrets People Make on their Deathbed By Bronnie Ware (who worked for years nursing the dying)&amp;hellip;When questioned about any regrets they had or anything they would do differently, common themes surfaced again and again. Here are the most common five:&#xA;I wish I’d had the courage to live a life true to myself, not the life others expected of me. This was the most common regret of all… read the full post here </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groups with more women are more intelligent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/women-and-group-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/women-and-group-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>Tom Malone on collective intelligence and the “genetic” structure of groups&#xA;The average intelligence of the people in the group and the maximum intelligence of the people in the group doesn’t predict group intelligence.&#xA;and&#xA;So how do you engineer groups that can problem-solve effectively? First of all, seed them with, basically, caring people. Group intelligence is correlated … with the average social sensitivity — the openness, and receptiveness, to others — of a group’s constituents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rushkoff, a change agent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ruskoff-a-change-agent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ruskoff-a-change-agent/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading two books by Douglas Rushkoff. &amp;ldquo;Program or Be Programmed&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Life Inc&amp;rdquo;. These books have well reasoned arguments that encourage a subversive approach to two pervasive elements of modern life&#xA;The rise of technocratic class that you should join before they take control of to many aspects of your life A fundamental challenge to our modern economic model and the way that plays out in our jobs and life choices This is fascinating stuff and fits into a rare category of books that change the way you view the world around you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trading as video game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/trading-and-video-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/trading-and-video-games/</guid>
      <description>An interesting article from the Atlantic which compares the modern derivates trading environment with playing a sophisticated computer game.&#xA;Trading as a high-stakes video game&#xA;Worth reading through as it speculates that the scenario described will become a component of more jobs in the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Great bookshops of the world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/great-bookshops-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/great-bookshops-of-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Fascinating photos of bookshops from around in the world in the this article in Salon via Twitter from Mark Bertstein who has been to 3 of them. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I have been to the final one in San Francisco, may visit the London shop this year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things that matter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/things-that-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/things-that-matter/</guid>
      <description>Seth Godin has published a free ebook, &amp;ldquo;Things that matter&amp;rdquo;. It contains over 70 short essays from todays leading thinkers. Definitely worth a read. I found resonances in many of the entries however the following extract from Howard Mann caught my attention as its a phenonmena I see growing daily.&#xA;We walk the streets with our heads down staring into 3-inch screens while the world whisks by doing the same. And yet we’re convinced we are more connected to each other than ever before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal Eating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/seasonal-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/seasonal-eating/</guid>
      <description>The way to keep the food miles down is to eat in sync with whats in season for your region. Its a simple idea that would once have been the only option for most people. In modern first world countries it now requires an effort to know what is in season and to track down local producers. If you have a local farmers market then patronise it well so the producers keep going to the trouble of turning up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balehaus - an experimental building</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/balehaus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/balehaus/</guid>
      <description>The Ecologist is one of the great journals of the green movement and has recently gone through the transformation from print to online. This makes access to its stimulating content much easier.&#xA;Click here to read about an interesting prototype building just opened at Bath university that uses pre-fabricated wall panels filled with straw.&#xA;The Bath University Balehaus project site is worth a look.&#xA;When will we have access to locally produced building products like this in Australia I wonder ?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New book - cubicle nation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cubicle-nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cubicle-nation/</guid>
      <description>Nice to see Pamela Slim&amp;rsquo;s book in the shops, I am looking forward to giving it a read after enjoying her blog for some time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traditional chicken ark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/chicken-ark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/chicken-ark/</guid>
      <description>Here is a design for a traditional chicken ark. This is from Charles Hayward&amp;rsquo;s 1940 book &amp;ldquo;Carpentry for Beginners&amp;rdquo; which has still a useful reference as it shows hand tool methods (even better is &amp;ldquo;Cabinet Making for Beginners&amp;rdquo;).&#xA;Click here for the full PDF -&amp;gt; How to build a chicken ark</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In season zen cooking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/zen-cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/zen-cooking/</guid>
      <description>Nice post here at Mother Earth News Stop Putting Off Chickens&#xA;In season down in Sydney at the moment (from the Slow Food Sydney newsletter)&#xA;Strawberries Spinach and watercress Valencia oranges Asparagus Ethical Eating book reviewed in the Eco Pages of the Sydney Morning Herald&#xA;We rented a great DVD - How to Cook Your Life should be very interesting to anyone who still has a yellowing copy of the Tassajara cookbook or bread book as it features Ed Brown who also wrote those books back in the 70&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So long Fourth World Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fourth-world-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fourth-world-review/</guid>
      <description>I am a great fan of subversive media that seeks to tell truths that do not sit easily in the tomes of the major outlets, being dictated as they are by large advertising revenue and they need to appeal to as wide an audience as possible.&#xA;For several years now I have been sporadically receiving a small journal called the Fourth World Review. The wonderful polemic was the work of John Papworth a great eccentric of the type only Britain seems to produce.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BEN - bicycle empowerment network</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/bicycle-empowerment-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/bicycle-empowerment-network/</guid>
      <description>Its Blog Action Day - my plug is for BEN the Bicycle Empowerment Network of Namibia.&#xA;Established by Australian Michael Linke who had previously edited Australian Cyclist, which at the time was Australia&amp;rsquo;s largest circulation cycling magazine, and ReNew, a magazine aimed at people designing, making and using solar, wind and biofuel energy devices, lowering their energy consumption and designing environmentally sustainable houses and businesses.&#xA;Since starting in May 2005, they have distributed more than 7,000 bicycles, 80 bicycle ambulances and 9 community-based bicycle workshops.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alan Watts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/alan-watts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/alan-watts/</guid>
      <description>Reading Alan Watts in my teens I experienced my first taste of eastern thinking which has led to a life long interest. In his essays on Zen and the Tao I could feel deep truths were lurking just beyond the words. A particular favourite is Cloud-hidden, Whereabouts Unknown: A Mountain Journal.&#xA;This collection of essays and transcribed lectures was compiled in 1973 shortly before his death. Watts was an enigmatic character who during this latter period of his life lived on a houseboat moored near San Francisco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Urban chickens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/urban-chickens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/urban-chickens/</guid>
      <description>Eating Locally: Backyard Chickens at Treehugger.com. Keeping chickens in the urban backyards was commonplace in Australia during the depression and war years and is making a welcome comeback. I wonder how many people are actually able to kill and eat their chickens. I have tried and it takes some getting used to!. Having the chooks for eggs alone is the easier route and very worthwhile as we have posted about before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More on chicken tractors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/more-on-chicken-tractors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/more-on-chicken-tractors/</guid>
      <description>Since my post about chickens which mentioned the Linda Woodrow inspired chook dome. I have noticed that people are searching in google for information about chicken tractors. This post provides a few more links to information on this subject.&#xA;The Chicken Tractor gallery has over 140 pictures with many different types shown. As the construction skills required are very basic, a good picture will often be enough for you to build your own using materials to hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity amongst the weapons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/simpicity-amongst-the-weapons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/simpicity-amongst-the-weapons/</guid>
      <description>This week we went to the opening night of a new movie - Son Of A Lion. This is a moving and engaging story set in the tribal region of northern Pakistan, home of the Pashtuns. The typical depiction of Pashtuns in contemporary media brands them as extremist terrorists and followers of Osama Bin Laden. This is not the case for much of the population including those in this simple story.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notebooks and Manifestos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/notebooks-and-manifestos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/notebooks-and-manifestos/</guid>
      <description>I have love notebooks, especially interesting quirky ones that help me feel creative.&#xA;My latest notebook is the Makers Notebook from Make magazine. Its modelled after a lab book with graph paper pages. Solidly bound and with loads and useful (and just plain weird) data in the back pages. Included in the book are two manifestos, The Makers Bill of Rights and a Crafters Manifesto. Here is an extract&#xA;People get satisfaction for being able to create/craft things because they can see themselves in the objects they make.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting things off</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/putting-things-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/putting-things-off/</guid>
      <description>Putting Things Off has a nice post about changing the way we work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whats lurking under the lid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/lurking-under-the-lid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/lurking-under-the-lid/</guid>
      <description>Many of us have been aware of many of the dangers associated with processed foods and the artificial chemicals introduced by the food industry for some time. I was reminded of the horror story again recent after reading Michael Pollans excellent book In Defence of Food.&#xA;The book starts with a blistering criticism of &amp;ldquo;nutritionism&amp;rdquo; - his term for the ideology that underlies much of the food marketing and health food industry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A slow sunday at the art gallery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-sunday-art-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-sunday-art-gallery/</guid>
      <description>We wandered along to the Art Gallery of NSW today for our Slow Sunday. I wanted to take another look at the Harold Cazneaux exhibition. It is the most inspiring collection of photographic images. Wonderful use of light and location, especially when you consider the equipment that he was using compared to what we have available today. The images are highly atmospheric and clearly present themselves as art.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Cazneaux was the leading exponent in Australia of the school of &amp;lsquo;pictorial photography.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The franklin river campaign - 25 years on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-franklin-river-campaign-25-years-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-franklin-river-campaign-25-years-on/</guid>
      <description>25 years since the Franklin River Campaign&#xA;In July 1983 the Australian High Court ruled the Franklin Dam could be stopped by the new Federal Labour Government against the wishes of the Tasmanian State government.&#xA;Prior to this over 1000 people from all over Australia and the world had travelled down to the river site camps and been arrested in a mass act of civil disobedience.&#xA;I was there with a number of friends and it was one of the defining experiences of my life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The franklin river campaign - 25 years on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-franklin-river-campaign-25-years-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-franklin-river-campaign-25-years-on/</guid>
      <description>25 years since the Franklin River Campaign&#xA;In July 1983 the Australian High Court ruled the Franklin Dam could be stopped by the new Federal Labour Government against the wishes of the Tasmanian State government.&#xA;Prior to this over 1000 people from all over Australia and the world had travelled down to the river site camps and been arrested in a mass act of civil disobedience.&#xA;I was there with a number of friends and it was one of the defining experiences of my life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resurgence slow sundays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-sundays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-sundays/</guid>
      <description>The latest issue of Resurgence has arrived and it looks a beauty. At quick skim reveals the usual combination of thoughtful articles and fabulous images.&#xA;In the spirit of Ghandi&amp;rsquo;s use of spinning as an act of defiance, Resurgence have chosen baking bread as the theme of their first Slow Sunday.&#xA;In each issue of the magazine we will nominate one Sunday when we invite our members to take part in simple actions that symbolise a rejection of commercialism, a passion for the planet and a desire for change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shakuhachi festival world masters concert</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/shakuhachi-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/shakuhachi-festival/</guid>
      <description>Just returned from a concert that was the major public event of the 5th World Shakuhachi Festival. This gathering was a rare opportunity to see and hear some of the worlds foremost players and was an extraordinary experience. Tonights concert featured pieces played on Shakuhachi, Koto, Shamisen and harp. A musical and accomplished Australian Aboriginal welcome ceremony was performed by Matthew Doyle. A mass playing of Temuke by the festival participants was a highlight.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visit to hepburn springs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/hepburn-springs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/hepburn-springs/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re just back from a few days at Hepburn Springs in the Victorian Spa country. Its a beautiful area, quite cold at this time of year but still a rewarding place to stay and unwind.&#xA;We wanted to stay in Australia&amp;rsquo;s only Ryokan (a traditional Japanese Inn) - Shizuka. It was extremely peaceful and served beautiful Japanese food, although the futon was starting to feel a bit hard towards the end of our stay!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biodynamic wine in the news</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/biodynamic-wine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/biodynamic-wine/</guid>
      <description>Michelle Gadd of organicwine.com.au has a good summary of recent coverage of biodynamic wine in the Australia media.&#xA;With lots of recent media interest in biodynamic wine producers the rest of the world is starting to discover the absolute quality of biodynamic wines.&#xA;She is offering some excellent mixed cases of Australian biodynamic wines including the Krinklewood Vordelho mentioned here on Slowlane recently.&#xA;Her new Catalog also has a special on a mixed box of Tamburlaine organic wine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chilly chook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/chilly-chook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/chilly-chook/</guid>
      <description>While browsing the website of designer Zach Debord (found via a Make RSS post) I came across this great picture of a chook in the snow with a jumper on, she looks very cosy. Head over to their site to see more of these pictures in a slideshow.&#xA;Their blog has quite a few posts about their chickens and burgeoning interest in Permaculture.&#xA;Worth a look.&#xA;For the those with a technical bent Zach&amp;rsquo;s beam robots are stunning works that merge art and electronics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pursuing a simpler life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-simpler-lfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-simpler-lfe/</guid>
      <description>Zen Habits a frequent and popular contributor of articles that cover many aspects of moving towards a simpler life have published a summary of their articles focused on simplicity.&#xA;Check it out </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guerrilla bagging</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/guerilla-bagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/guerilla-bagging/</guid>
      <description>Horrified to discover the damage that plastic bags were causing to our marine environment, Claire Morsman devised a plan for action - &amp;lsquo;sociable guerrilla bagging&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;The idea is that people make reusable bags from recycled material and then give them away to friends and family or sometimes during mass handouts.&#xA;Since it began in January 2007, hundreds of people working alone or in &amp;ldquo;pods&amp;rdquo; who work together on the bags have made over 20,000 bags.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healing power of chooks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/healing-power-of-chooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/healing-power-of-chooks/</guid>
      <description>This post has been in my mind since I saw a wonderful program ABC TV. The program “Rare Chicken Rescue” has two themes, one is depression and the other is about rescuing rare chicken breeds. Both subjects are interesting however it was the role that keeping chickens played in rescuing Mark Tully from depression that really struck a chord.&#xA;When we lived on the North Coast of NSW we kept about 20 odd chickens and 3 ducks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frightened by voluntary simplicity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/voluntary-simplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/voluntary-simplicity/</guid>
      <description>An article in the New York Times here tells of a couple who are shedding their possessions prior to starting a new life as organic farmers. What I found interesting was that they have had some hostile reactions on the blog they are keeping to document the journey. I suspect that many people find the idea of others who are stepping outside the norm and “letting it all go by” to be threatening.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organic vs local</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/organic-vs-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/organic-vs-local/</guid>
      <description>These days we have a reasonable range of organic food available to us locally whether through the supermarket, our local shops and/or box deliveries. However, in common with nearly all modern food, much of it travels substantial distances before it gets to us. In addition it is often out of season for our local environs. This has created a modern conundrum where shoppers seeking to buy organic must often choose a product with many air and road miles included in its true cost of availability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A very small farm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-very-small-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-very-small-farm/</guid>
      <description>When I considered which of my favourite books to write about for this blog, one of the first to come to mind was William Paul Winchester&amp;rsquo;s wonderful memoir of life on his 20 acres - A Very Small Farm.&#xA;This is a book to pick up over the years and read a few pages, just for the enjoyment of immersing yourself in the manifest simplicity of Winchester&amp;rsquo;s life. Divided into chapters that are essentially diary entries, you are drawn into the joy he experiences from being engaged in the world around him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krinklewood biodynamic wine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/krinklewood-biodynamic-vineyard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/krinklewood-biodynamic-vineyard/</guid>
      <description>The Krinklewood vineyard was recently given a positive review in the local media so I thought I would give it a try. We would have gotten around to it anyway as we are very keen on organic and biodynamic wines. So last night I picked up a bottle of the 2007 Verdelho which we tried with some high quality lebanese food at a local restaurant. Wow, this is a delicious wine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slow food university</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-food-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-food-university/</guid>
      <description>When Slowlane joined Slow Food recently they sent a booklet outlining their various initiatives, The Slow Food Companion. Two ventures that sounded particularly interesting were the University of Gastronic Sciences (UNISG) and the Terre Madre. The university is based in Piedmont and claims to be the first academic institution in the world dedicated to the study of gastronomy. Subjects include Botany, Food Technology, History of Agriculture, Sensory Analysis and Anthropology. The curriculum combines humanities and sciences with food technology and culture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New perspectives on money</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/money-perspectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/money-perspectives/</guid>
      <description>The May/June issue of Resurgence has arrived and it looks very interesting.&#xA;Its a special focus issue titled &amp;ldquo;The money delusion: In search of true wealth&amp;rdquo;. It kicks off with an excellent editorial from Satish Kumar which introduces the topic.&#xA;Here are a few quotes to give you a flavour of the article:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Let us be clear. Money is not wealth. It is a delusion to think that money is wealth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing information overload</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/information-overload/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/information-overload/</guid>
      <description>Saw this great cartoon over at Devon-Technologies which I have been visiting lately as I start to tackle my own information overload.&#xA;Devon-Technologies make some very sophisticated software for the mac, I am exploring DevonThink Professional, an amazingly powerful database.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australian Organic Wine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/organic-wine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/organic-wine/</guid>
      <description>Here in Australia we have a vibrant wine industry including an increasing number of vineyards producing organic and/or biodynamic wine. We are especially keen on the wines from Mudgee in central NSW. This is a dry inland region that is ideal for organic growing due to the lack of humidity which reduces the amount of mould and fungus problems compared to locations closer to the coast, these are generally treated using chemical sprays.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clear thinking - well informed outspoken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/clear-thinking-and-outspoken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/clear-thinking-and-outspoken/</guid>
      <description>No its not this author, although we can aspire&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m referring to George Monbiot, who&amp;rsquo;s new book Bring on the Apocalypse - Six Arguments for Global Justice has leapt to the top of my reading pile. To do that it displaced Nicholas Shakespeares book Secrets of the Sea which I reserved at the library with great anticipation due to my attachment to stories about Tasmania. Not to mention any number of magazines and other tempting material.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
