<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Craft on Slowlane</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/craft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Craft on Slowlane</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/craft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sydney Ceramics Galleries</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/sydney-ceramics-galleries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/sydney-ceramics-galleries/</guid>
      <description>There are some excellent galleries in Sydney that focus on displaying the work of local artists and providing exhibition space.&#xA;I am sure its a labour of love for most of the gallery owners as the market is not large and the work required to mount a successful exhibition is signifcant.&#xA;Chinaclay Kerrie Lowe Sabbia If in the mood to travel further afield, the galley at the Sturt College in Mittagong always has an eclectic mix of work in particular furniture and ceramics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ceramic Destinations in Tokyo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ceramics-destinations-in-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ceramics-destinations-in-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>The most popular post on Slowlane has been Ceramics Destinations in Kyoto, this post seeks to provide the same information for a Tokyo visitor.&#xA;Mingeikan Also known as the Japan Folk Crafts Museum. Soetsu Yanagi 1 created this museum to display his collection of mingei items (daily necessities made by common people using local materials)It displays a collection of mingei pottery, textiles and lacquer ware. Feature exhibitions are also held regularly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arkansas Living Treasures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/arkansas-living-treasures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/arkansas-living-treasures/</guid>
      <description>Following a link from Fine Woodworking I came across an inspiring collection of videos featuring a group of traditional craftspeople who live in the US state of Arkansas.&#xA;The state has sponsored the production of a movie series featuring each craftsman talking about their work and practising in their studios.&#xA;Something that stands out is the advanced age of some of the artists who are still practising. Chair maker Dallas Bump is 94 and fiddle maker Violet Hensley was still making well into her 90&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making and Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/making-and-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/making-and-work/</guid>
      <description>I describe myself as a Maker, for me the term is a indicator of where my inspiration and satisfaction are found. This has generally been realised in the workshop making objects with wood and more recently clay. Its harder to find in the work I do as a Solution and Enterprise architect. Aspects are definitely present, as myself or my team are generally involved with a larger to team to create and implement a new software capability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making a Flamenco Guitar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/making-a-flamenco-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/making-a-flamenco-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I have linked to this video showing the making of a beautiful guitar before, but its so good its worth another run.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We should build mandolins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/we-should-build-mandolins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/we-should-build-mandolins/</guid>
      <description>Here is another beautiful video celebrating craftsmanship.&#xA;It features Tom Ellis who started building mandolins from his rural workshop in late 1970&amp;rsquo;s. Tom has recently relaunched his instrument line in collaboration with Pava one his co-workers.&#xA;The video was produced by the Fretboard Journal a very high quality magazine that features stories and photo&amp;rsquo;s about guitars, players and makers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jean Nicholas Gerard, a potters potter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-potters-potter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-potters-potter/</guid>
      <description>Goldmark have produced another fascinating &amp;ldquo;day in the life&amp;rdquo; video, this time featuring French potter Jean-Nicholas Gerard who makes beautiful slipware pots.&#xA;Although these videos are obviously produced to promote the artists ahead of upcoming exhibitions at Goldmark, they are in themselves a tremendous service to the ceramics community. The gentle pace and broad scope allow the viewer to be transported into the rhythm of these artists lives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Makers at work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/makers-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/makers-at-work/</guid>
      <description>There is an extensive collection of videos of showcasing makers and their work, at Those Who Make.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s one I particularly enjoyed</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Craftsmanship, one mans inspiration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/craftsmanship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/craftsmanship/</guid>
      <description>Moving essay from David Sparks meditating about the influence of his father on his own pursuit of craftsmanship. I am sure that many modern craftsman were inspired to take up the tools for similar reasons, I certainly was growing up in a household where Dad always had a project on the go.&#xA;Craftsmanship and My Father — MacSparky</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Made by hand in brooklyn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/made-by-hand-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/made-by-hand-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>Made by Hand is a project creating beautiful videos that celebrate the resurgent maker scene in Brooklyn. Also see this page.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;Made by Hand was created out of the belief that the things we collect, consume, use, and share are part of who we are as individuals. For example, the food that we eat says something about each of us, as do the tools we use and the chairs we rest on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Dermer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-visit-to-john-dermer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-visit-to-john-dermer/</guid>
      <description>In November we travelled down to Kirby&amp;rsquo;s Flat for John Dermer&amp;rsquo;s annual major exhibition.&#xA;Planning to be there early we stayed overnight in Beechworth and arrived at Johns pottery at 10 past nine, assuming we would be the first car in the car park. What a surprise to find about a dozen cars already parked up, even more of a shock was waiting for us when we entered the gallery to find half of the exhibits already proudly bearing their red stickers indicating they were sold.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swedish spoon-maker 1923</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/spoon-maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/spoon-maker/</guid>
      <description>Great video link from The Village Carpenter</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Anarchists Tool Chest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/anarchists-toolchest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/anarchists-toolchest/</guid>
      <description>Just finished reading the Anarchists Tool Chest by Christopher Schwartz. Its inspired me to build my own chest and stock with it quality tools made where possible by small firms and individuals who are keeping the tools needed for traditional woodworking alive. Chris has wicked sense of humour which, once I tuned into it, added a nice touch of levity to the material.&#xA;The book is about what Chris describes as the essential set of tools needed to practise traditional hand tool woodworking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ceramics Destinations in Kyoto</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ceramics-destinations-in-kyoto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ceramics-destinations-in-kyoto/</guid>
      <description>The following are worth considering if you are in Kyoto and interested in Ceramics.&#xA;Kawai Kanjiros&amp;rsquo; House We have visited this beautiful old merchants house with its huge climbing kiln several times and always found it rewarding. The enormous climbing kiln and beautifully preserved house are worth spending some time exploring.&#xA;Kawai Kanjiro was a key player in Soetsu Yanangi&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Mingei&amp;rdquo; movement1 in partnership Shoji Hamada, Kenichi Tomimoto and Bernard Leach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mike dodd video</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/mike-dodd-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/mike-dodd-video/</guid>
      <description>Mike Dodd makes beautiful ceramics.&#xA;Goldmark have produced an uplifting video of Mike talking about his work and life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A cabinet makers notebook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-cabinetmakers-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-cabinetmakers-notebook/</guid>
      <description>In interviews with contemporary woodworkers James Krenov’s first book ‘A Cabinetmaker Notebook’ is often cited as the book that changed the course of that person’s life and led to them pursuing a career with wood.&#xA;The book is a meditation on Krenov’s approach to his work. It describes a sensitive and considered approach to the design and construction of several pieces with a friendly conversational tone.&#xA;I stand at my workbench.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guerrilla bagging</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/guerilla-bagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/guerilla-bagging/</guid>
      <description>Horrified to discover the damage that plastic bags were causing to our marine environment, Claire Morsman devised a plan for action - &amp;lsquo;sociable guerrilla bagging&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;The idea is that people make reusable bags from recycled material and then give them away to friends and family or sometimes during mass handouts.&#xA;Since it began in January 2007, hundreds of people working alone or in &amp;ldquo;pods&amp;rdquo; who work together on the bags have made over 20,000 bags.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
