<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food on Slowlane</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/food/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food on Slowlane</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Lucky Find</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-lucky-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-lucky-find/</guid>
      <description>Reading John Connell’s “The Running Book” with its evocative portrayal of the Irish landscape prompted me to dig out this catalogue of black &amp;amp; white photographs by Giles Norman. I seem to remember we picked it up at his studio in Kinsale back in the early 1990’s. Beautiful moody landscape and street photography.&#xA;We also had the best Seafood Chowder ever at a pub by the beach at Kinsale1. Since then all Seafood Chowders have been measure against the Kinsale Scale.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture Online Course Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-online-course-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-online-course-update/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I wrote about the positive experience we were having taking part in Geoff Lawton&amp;rsquo;s Online Permaculture course. Having completed all the online lessons and the quiz we are now working on the practical assignment which is due by the end of August.&#xA;The course continues to stimulate us and our enthusiasm for the material remains strong. Even on evenings when we were tired from a busy day the prospect of some &amp;ldquo;Geoff time&amp;rdquo; was appealing and we had little trouble keeping up the momentum and staying more or less in line with the proposed course outline.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture and online learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-and-online-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-and-online-learning/</guid>
      <description>After years of exposure to Permaculture and having spent several years a decade ago implementing a disparate set of its common patterns at our previous property in Northern NSW, I am now taking a much deeper dive into it after enrolling in Geoff Lawton&amp;rsquo;s Online Permaculture Design Course. Its been running a few weeks now and my partner and I are both finding it a revelation. So many concepts and themes that we had previously read about but not really understood are suddenly making sense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prioritising organic foods and challenges to paleo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/organic-foods-and-paleo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/organic-foods-and-paleo/</guid>
      <description>Mark Sisson runs a business that promotes a version of the Paleo diet and philosophy (Primal). He writes some excellent posts on his blog that I often find myself nodding in agreement with. A recent post that suggests a prioritised list of what to buy from organic sources is an example.&#xA;What Foods to Buy Organic&#xA;I like this list. In addition, its also important to consider&#xA;Animal welfare. Always look for evidence of best practises in animal welfare and support these growers and suppliers Sourcing food outside of the large supermarket monopolies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A look behind the increasing prevalence of supermarket-organic-products</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/supermarket-organics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/supermarket-organics/</guid>
      <description>Is Organic Supermarket Food a Lie? Revealing look behind the supermarket green wash. The example is from Europe however it is surely just as relevant here in Australia. The call to action&#xA;Here is what we can do starting today&#xA;* Stop supporting industrial food by buying it. Organic is better than conventional, but still not good.&#xA;* Build relationships with small local farmers that believe in quality and practice sustainable agriculture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinas rising soybean consumption-reshaping-western-agriculture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/chinas-soybean-consumption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/chinas-soybean-consumption/</guid>
      <description>Disturbing article by Lester Brown on the PRI website&#xA;&amp;ldquo;..Put simply, saving the Amazon rainforest now depends on curbing the growth in demand for soybeans by stabilizing population worldwide as soon as possible. And for the world’s more affluent people, it means eating less meat and thus slowing the growth in demand for soybeans…&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Where was once pristine Amazon rainforest, soybean harvesters march across the landscape instead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal Eating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/seasonal-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/seasonal-eating/</guid>
      <description>The way to keep the food miles down is to eat in sync with whats in season for your region. Its a simple idea that would once have been the only option for most people. In modern first world countries it now requires an effort to know what is in season and to track down local producers. If you have a local farmers market then patronise it well so the producers keep going to the trouble of turning up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traditional chicken ark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/chicken-ark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/chicken-ark/</guid>
      <description>Here is a design for a traditional chicken ark. This is from Charles Hayward&amp;rsquo;s 1940 book &amp;ldquo;Carpentry for Beginners&amp;rdquo; which has still a useful reference as it shows hand tool methods (even better is &amp;ldquo;Cabinet Making for Beginners&amp;rdquo;).&#xA;Click here for the full PDF -&amp;gt; How to build a chicken ark</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In season zen cooking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/zen-cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/zen-cooking/</guid>
      <description>Nice post here at Mother Earth News Stop Putting Off Chickens&#xA;In season down in Sydney at the moment (from the Slow Food Sydney newsletter)&#xA;Strawberries Spinach and watercress Valencia oranges Asparagus Ethical Eating book reviewed in the Eco Pages of the Sydney Morning Herald&#xA;We rented a great DVD - How to Cook Your Life should be very interesting to anyone who still has a yellowing copy of the Tassajara cookbook or bread book as it features Ed Brown who also wrote those books back in the 70&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Urban chickens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/urban-chickens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/urban-chickens/</guid>
      <description>Eating Locally: Backyard Chickens at Treehugger.com. Keeping chickens in the urban backyards was commonplace in Australia during the depression and war years and is making a welcome comeback. I wonder how many people are actually able to kill and eat their chickens. I have tried and it takes some getting used to!. Having the chooks for eggs alone is the easier route and very worthwhile as we have posted about before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More on chicken tractors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/more-on-chicken-tractors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/more-on-chicken-tractors/</guid>
      <description>Since my post about chickens which mentioned the Linda Woodrow inspired chook dome. I have noticed that people are searching in google for information about chicken tractors. This post provides a few more links to information on this subject.&#xA;The Chicken Tractor gallery has over 140 pictures with many different types shown. As the construction skills required are very basic, a good picture will often be enough for you to build your own using materials to hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biodynamic wine in the news</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/biodynamic-wine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/biodynamic-wine/</guid>
      <description>Michelle Gadd of organicwine.com.au has a good summary of recent coverage of biodynamic wine in the Australia media.&#xA;With lots of recent media interest in biodynamic wine producers the rest of the world is starting to discover the absolute quality of biodynamic wines.&#xA;She is offering some excellent mixed cases of Australian biodynamic wines including the Krinklewood Vordelho mentioned here on Slowlane recently.&#xA;Her new Catalog also has a special on a mixed box of Tamburlaine organic wine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organic vs local</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/organic-vs-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/organic-vs-local/</guid>
      <description>These days we have a reasonable range of organic food available to us locally whether through the supermarket, our local shops and/or box deliveries. However, in common with nearly all modern food, much of it travels substantial distances before it gets to us. In addition it is often out of season for our local environs. This has created a modern conundrum where shoppers seeking to buy organic must often choose a product with many air and road miles included in its true cost of availability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krinklewood biodynamic wine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/krinklewood-biodynamic-vineyard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/krinklewood-biodynamic-vineyard/</guid>
      <description>The Krinklewood vineyard was recently given a positive review in the local media so I thought I would give it a try. We would have gotten around to it anyway as we are very keen on organic and biodynamic wines. So last night I picked up a bottle of the 2007 Verdelho which we tried with some high quality lebanese food at a local restaurant. Wow, this is a delicious wine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slow food university</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-food-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-food-university/</guid>
      <description>When Slowlane joined Slow Food recently they sent a booklet outlining their various initiatives, The Slow Food Companion. Two ventures that sounded particularly interesting were the University of Gastronic Sciences (UNISG) and the Terre Madre. The university is based in Piedmont and claims to be the first academic institution in the world dedicated to the study of gastronomy. Subjects include Botany, Food Technology, History of Agriculture, Sensory Analysis and Anthropology. The curriculum combines humanities and sciences with food technology and culture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australian Organic Wine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/organic-wine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/organic-wine/</guid>
      <description>Here in Australia we have a vibrant wine industry including an increasing number of vineyards producing organic and/or biodynamic wine. We are especially keen on the wines from Mudgee in central NSW. This is a dry inland region that is ideal for organic growing due to the lack of humidity which reduces the amount of mould and fungus problems compared to locations closer to the coast, these are generally treated using chemical sprays.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
