<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Earth on Slowlane</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/earth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Earth on Slowlane</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/earth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Inhabit Movie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/inhabit-movie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/inhabit-movie/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2013 a couple of filmmakers bravely took on the risk of making a high quality movie about the Permaculture movement in North America. Once they had shot the footage, they launched a kickstarter project to raise funds to complete the project last year.&#xA;The movie, Inhabit was recently released. Its availble from Vimeo and also through the Yekra project, an innovative distribution channel that enables media creators to sell their product without having to deal with the traditional players.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture Online Course Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-online-course-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-online-course-update/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I wrote about the positive experience we were having taking part in Geoff Lawton&amp;rsquo;s Online Permaculture course. Having completed all the online lessons and the quiz we are now working on the practical assignment which is due by the end of August.&#xA;The course continues to stimulate us and our enthusiasm for the material remains strong. Even on evenings when we were tired from a busy day the prospect of some &amp;ldquo;Geoff time&amp;rdquo; was appealing and we had little trouble keeping up the momentum and staying more or less in line with the proposed course outline.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture and online learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-and-online-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-and-online-learning/</guid>
      <description>After years of exposure to Permaculture and having spent several years a decade ago implementing a disparate set of its common patterns at our previous property in Northern NSW, I am now taking a much deeper dive into it after enrolling in Geoff Lawton&amp;rsquo;s Online Permaculture Design Course. Its been running a few weeks now and my partner and I are both finding it a revelation. So many concepts and themes that we had previously read about but not really understood are suddenly making sense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The way of the megapode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/megapode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/megapode/</guid>
      <description>I am with but she&amp;rsquo;s a girl, being a fan of Douglas Adam&amp;rsquo;s book Last Chance to See. As I am also in interested in scripting and other geekery, this post hit all the right notes.&#xA;Our local Megapodes are known as Bush (or Brush) Turkey&amp;rsquo;s and can destroy a productive vege path in seconds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attack of the wolf mountain chickens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/wolf-mountain-chickens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/wolf-mountain-chickens/</guid>
      <description>This chook post has it all - video, pictures, domes and self feeders. Also some great insight into the chicken management practises at Milkwood Permaculture.&#xA;Attack of the Wolf Mountain Chickens&#xA;(Via Milkwood Permaculture.)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balehaus - an experimental building</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/balehaus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/balehaus/</guid>
      <description>The Ecologist is one of the great journals of the green movement and has recently gone through the transformation from print to online. This makes access to its stimulating content much easier.&#xA;Click here to read about an interesting prototype building just opened at Bath university that uses pre-fabricated wall panels filled with straw.&#xA;The Bath University Balehaus project site is worth a look.&#xA;When will we have access to locally produced building products like this in Australia I wonder ?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traditional chicken ark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/chicken-ark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/chicken-ark/</guid>
      <description>Here is a design for a traditional chicken ark. This is from Charles Hayward&amp;rsquo;s 1940 book &amp;ldquo;Carpentry for Beginners&amp;rdquo; which has still a useful reference as it shows hand tool methods (even better is &amp;ldquo;Cabinet Making for Beginners&amp;rdquo;).&#xA;Click here for the full PDF -&amp;gt; How to build a chicken ark</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Urban chickens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/urban-chickens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/urban-chickens/</guid>
      <description>Eating Locally: Backyard Chickens at Treehugger.com. Keeping chickens in the urban backyards was commonplace in Australia during the depression and war years and is making a welcome comeback. I wonder how many people are actually able to kill and eat their chickens. I have tried and it takes some getting used to!. Having the chooks for eggs alone is the easier route and very worthwhile as we have posted about before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More on chicken tractors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/more-on-chicken-tractors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/more-on-chicken-tractors/</guid>
      <description>Since my post about chickens which mentioned the Linda Woodrow inspired chook dome. I have noticed that people are searching in google for information about chicken tractors. This post provides a few more links to information on this subject.&#xA;The Chicken Tractor gallery has over 140 pictures with many different types shown. As the construction skills required are very basic, a good picture will often be enough for you to build your own using materials to hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healing power of chooks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/healing-power-of-chooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/healing-power-of-chooks/</guid>
      <description>This post has been in my mind since I saw a wonderful program ABC TV. The program “Rare Chicken Rescue” has two themes, one is depression and the other is about rescuing rare chicken breeds. Both subjects are interesting however it was the role that keeping chickens played in rescuing Mark Tully from depression that really struck a chord.&#xA;When we lived on the North Coast of NSW we kept about 20 odd chickens and 3 ducks.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
