<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spirit on Slowlane</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/spirit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spirit on Slowlane</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/spirit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Obstacles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/overcoming-obstacles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/overcoming-obstacles/</guid>
      <description>This inspirational talk by Nick White at the Wellington Ignite Conference gives an insight into what its like for an avid public speaker to overcome head and neck cancer and the loss of his voice. via Presentation Zen</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Apple of zen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-apple-of-zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-apple-of-zen/</guid>
      <description>Steve Jobs practised Zen! - the dharma talk below from teacher Peg Syverson (Appamada.org) considers Steve&amp;rsquo;s legacy and how to apply his approach to our lives.&#xA;Many people don’t even know that Steve Jobs practiced Zen. His teacher was Kobun Chino, a beloved Zen teacher who also performed Steve’s wedding to Laurene. Kobun Chino died in 2002 trying to save his five year old daughter Maya when she fell off a dock in Switzerland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This precious life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-precious-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-precious-life/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Because we don’t know when we will die, we get to think of life as an inexhaustible well. Yet everything happens only a certain number of times, and a very small number really. How many more times will you remember a certain afternoon of your childhood, an afternoon that is so deeply a part of your being that you can’t even conceive of your life without it? Perhaps four, five times more, perhaps not even that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 death bed regrets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/death-bed-regrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/death-bed-regrets/</guid>
      <description>Profound - timely.&#xA;Long Term Life Tips Top 5 Regrets People Make on their Deathbed By Bronnie Ware (who worked for years nursing the dying)&amp;hellip;When questioned about any regrets they had or anything they would do differently, common themes surfaced again and again. Here are the most common five:&#xA;I wish I’d had the courage to live a life true to myself, not the life others expected of me. This was the most common regret of all… read the full post here </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
