<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Slowlane</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Slowlane</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Lucky Find</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-lucky-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-lucky-find/</guid>
      <description>Reading John Connell’s “The Running Book” with its evocative portrayal of the Irish landscape prompted me to dig out this catalogue of black &amp;amp; white photographs by Giles Norman. I seem to remember we picked it up at his studio in Kinsale back in the early 1990’s. Beautiful moody landscape and street photography.&#xA;We also had the best Seafood Chowder ever at a pub by the beach at Kinsale1. Since then all Seafood Chowders have been measure against the Kinsale Scale.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture ethics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/permaculture-ethics/</guid>
      <description>I have been interested in Permaculture since 1980 when I stumbled upon a copy of Permaculture 2 in our local bookshop (the same shop also introduced me to The One Straw Revolution and Ecotopia around the same time).&#xA;Over the years I have experimented with various permaculture methods and been fortunate enough to meet Bill Mollison on a number of occasions. One of these was at the Tanelorn Music Festival held at Stroud in the Hunter Valley in 1981, not long after I had discovered the book.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Anarchists Tool Chest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/anarchists-toolchest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/anarchists-toolchest/</guid>
      <description>Just finished reading the Anarchists Tool Chest by Christopher Schwartz. Its inspired me to build my own chest and stock with it quality tools made where possible by small firms and individuals who are keeping the tools needed for traditional woodworking alive. Chris has wicked sense of humour which, once I tuned into it, added a nice touch of levity to the material.&#xA;The book is about what Chris describes as the essential set of tools needed to practise traditional hand tool woodworking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A cabinet makers notebook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-cabinetmakers-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-cabinetmakers-notebook/</guid>
      <description>In interviews with contemporary woodworkers James Krenov’s first book ‘A Cabinetmaker Notebook’ is often cited as the book that changed the course of that person’s life and led to them pursuing a career with wood.&#xA;The book is a meditation on Krenov’s approach to his work. It describes a sensitive and considered approach to the design and construction of several pieces with a friendly conversational tone.&#xA;I stand at my workbench.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guitar zero</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/guitar-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/guitar-zero/</guid>
      <description>I am reading a new book by Gary Marcus a scientist who in his professional life studies languages and cognitive science. In this book he explores the research behind the popular belief that its much more difficult for adults to learn a musical instrument compared to the ease with which children can pick it up. Gary had always harboured a desire to learn the guitar and the book follows his own journey to learn the guitar in his 40’s as he seeks to debunk the assumed wisdom that says its really to late for him to become competent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Read one book per week</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/one-book-per-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/one-book-per-week/</guid>
      <description>I will have to adopt an approach like Joshua Beck at Becoming Minimalist) if I am to reduce my reading backlog. Not to mention keeping up to date with exciting new books like those in the Tournament of Books.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drowning in books to read</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/drowning-in-books-to-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/drowning-in-books-to-read/</guid>
      <description>I love books, i enjoy being given them at this time of the year and I enjoy buying them at any time. Unfortunately I sometimes fall behind with reading them.&#xA;The to read pile has grown to the point where I decided I needed to create a list to keep track of them - Omnifocus to the rescue. Listing them like this should discourage me from acquiring any more until I have reduced this backlog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A book apart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-book-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-book-apart/</guid>
      <description>Just bought a bundle from A Book Apart, excellent value - especially as eBooks.&#xA;I already had the CSS3 book by Dan Cederholm and its a good little book. Its the little part that I particularly like, these days I find I do not have the time to work through large technical books and much prefer condensed focused works like the ones published by A Book Apart. Another thing they have right is providing multiple formats so I can read this on my Kindle and the Macbook Air, the prags led the way on this and another favourite publisher.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Great bookshops of the world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/great-bookshops-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/great-bookshops-of-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Fascinating photos of bookshops from around in the world in the this article in Salon via Twitter from Mark Bertstein who has been to 3 of them. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I have been to the final one in San Francisco, may visit the London shop this year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New book - cubicle nation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cubicle-nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cubicle-nation/</guid>
      <description>Nice to see Pamela Slim&amp;rsquo;s book in the shops, I am looking forward to giving it a read after enjoying her blog for some time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So long Fourth World Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fourth-world-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fourth-world-review/</guid>
      <description>I am a great fan of subversive media that seeks to tell truths that do not sit easily in the tomes of the major outlets, being dictated as they are by large advertising revenue and they need to appeal to as wide an audience as possible.&#xA;For several years now I have been sporadically receiving a small journal called the Fourth World Review. The wonderful polemic was the work of John Papworth a great eccentric of the type only Britain seems to produce.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alan Watts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/alan-watts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/alan-watts/</guid>
      <description>Reading Alan Watts in my teens I experienced my first taste of eastern thinking which has led to a life long interest. In his essays on Zen and the Tao I could feel deep truths were lurking just beyond the words. A particular favourite is Cloud-hidden, Whereabouts Unknown: A Mountain Journal.&#xA;This collection of essays and transcribed lectures was compiled in 1973 shortly before his death. Watts was an enigmatic character who during this latter period of his life lived on a houseboat moored near San Francisco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A very small farm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a-very-small-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a-very-small-farm/</guid>
      <description>When I considered which of my favourite books to write about for this blog, one of the first to come to mind was William Paul Winchester&amp;rsquo;s wonderful memoir of life on his 20 acres - A Very Small Farm.&#xA;This is a book to pick up over the years and read a few pages, just for the enjoyment of immersing yourself in the manifest simplicity of Winchester&amp;rsquo;s life. Divided into chapters that are essentially diary entries, you are drawn into the joy he experiences from being engaged in the world around him.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
